intellimusica.com 2019-09-02

# Privacy Policy

*Hi, it’s Evan. Given the new G.D.P.R. regulations, I figured it was time to display a _privacy policy_. I’ve created it in three parts: What I’m consciously/purposefully collecting with your express concent — my security initiatives — and normal browser/internet functioning, e.g., cookies, etc. For the latter, I borrowed and edited wording from author Tim Ferriss’s Privacy Policy — as it’s clear and concise. 

**This is the data I collect consciously with your express consent**

-I use a company called **Tinyletter to publish my email newsletter**. Obviously people enter their email, and I collect it [as part of my email list](https://tinyletter.com/ehandyside). I send members of my email list notification when I post a new guitar tab. I do not use this email for any other purpose. These emails will never be abused or shared with anyone.

If you receive emails from me, and no longer wish to, you can unsubscribe with one click at the base of the email. 

-My **Premium Members purchase and login through my paywall company Tinypass**. Tinypass is owned [by Piano Media.](https://piano.io/) When a Premium Member subscribes to my blog, I am only able to see their name, payment method (not details) and email. This info is only used by me when a Premium Member has a question about their account status.

If you’re Premium Member, and wish to unsubscribe from Intellimusica, you’ll do so through [your Tinypass dashboard.](https://www.intellimusica.com/goodbye/)

-If you **comment directly on this blog** , you’re prompted to enter your email address. This action is used to protect this Site from comment spam. Your email address is not displayed to the public. By default, your email is attached to the comment in the back-end (for my eyes only).

If you have left a comment directly on this blog, and would like your comment removed, email me at intellimusica@gmail.com. (This action will also remove the email address in the back end.)

**Implied consent (and no data collected)**

– **This website is an Amazon Affiliate**. If you click on an Amazon link (an purchase an item on Amazon) I’m paid a small % of the sale. In this case, all of your information is solely with Amazon. I’m not given any details other than what item was sold. These are sometimes referred to as Amazon Portals.

**My security initiatives**

This website is fully secure HTTPS site. The bulk of my security comes from my excellent hosting company, [pair Networks.](https://www.pair.com/) Their security includes: threat detection and blocking, malicious web application blocking, proactive security maintenance, and plug-in security monitoring.

My additional layer of security comes from 24/7 monitoring by Sucuri, Jetpack, and Wordfence.

Premium Members login through Tinypass/Piano Media which employs the highest security measures available.

###

Below is text that I borrowed from [author Tim Ferriss’s Privacy Policy](https://tim.blog/privacy-policy/). I’m a fan of his, and liked his wording on what I qualify as normal internet/browser functioning. I edited it down to what might pertain to this site, Intellimusica.

**Information that we collect and how we use it**

We collect your name and email address. For example, you may subscribe to receive email updates from the blog on the Site by submitting your email address. You also may submit comments to the blog on the Site or through the contact mechanism on the Site. We generally do not encourage the submission of any personal information in these comments or through the contact mechanism other than what we expressly require (e.g., name and email address). Information you disclose in the comments becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your information in a submission.

Web servers may automatically capture the following information from visitors to the Site, including the name of the domain and host from which you access the internet, the internet address of the Site from which you enter the Site, the pages you visit on the Site and the amount of time you spend on the Site.  This visitor information may be used to improve the Site.

**Disclosure of information**

We will not voluntarily share your name and email provided via the Site to any third party, except:

– To comply with legal requirements, such as law, regulation, warrant, subpoena, court order, or with a regulator or law enforcement agency or personnel.

**Links to other  ** **Websites**

We do not endorse and are not responsible for the information practices or privacy policies of any other Web sites that may be linked to or from the Site.  If you decide to access any other Web site that may be linked to or from the Site, you should consult that Web site’s privacy policy.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that the Site can place on your computer’s hard drive. When you visit the Site, a cookie may be placed on your computer for customizing and enhancing your experience on the Site. Your name and email address are not shared in this cookie. We use a cookie that collects anonymous traffic data. You can set your Web browser to block cookies, but doing so may affect your ability to access certain features of the Site.

**Children’s Privacy**

We will not knowingly collect personal information from children, e.g. email, etc. If we discover that a child has provided us with personal information, we will use reasonable efforts to delete this information.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may modify, alter or update this Privacy Policy at any time. We will not provide individual notice to you of changes to this Privacy Policy, but when we make updates to this Privacy Policy, we will update the date in this section.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on May, 29th 2018.
